Let's learn about inserting and know that beginning of this circular link at last.
And later on, we are going to learn about inserting a note at the end and then the middle and deleting
and searching for it at Circle Link and list and the notes inside that.
Consider this circle and could list contain three knowns.
The first one contains data 100.
The second contains data 200, and the third contains data equal to three hundred.
So we need to insert this note into the link, at least at the beginning, and I told you when you are
going to insert or delete, you should take care about that pointers and how to make the linkage between
the newly created or the deleted note with it, with the rest of the notes.
So take care about this notes.
But in order to insert it at the beginning, we need to link it and the change is there and to break
that linkage of the circular link, at least from the last one, and to point it to the newly created
one.
Let's see how we can do this is the newly created note.
It contains 400 and it's at index address four thousand twenty four.
We need to create a linkage.
From the last one to the first one to this newly created one.
But the point now it's at 1024 would change 1024 to four thousand twenty four.
This is the average of that newly created one.
Now the linkage of the the old one, which is the head disappears and we need to add that next pointer
to this.
So we need to add that next to the 1024.
OK.
This is the trick behind inserting at the beginning and the circular link at last.
So two things that you should take care.
We need to care about that.
And and the circular link between the last note and the first note and the link between the first note
that we have inserted and the next note.
So we have changed two addresses.
The first one, which was the last note that points now to the newly created one and the newly created
one.
The next point to it would refer to the 1024.
Let's see how to do that in code.
OK.
Let's create a method called at first.
We have created that point there had equal to null.
And now at first contains a court took into petty meter in fact invalid in this case in this animation,
and that we have in this example is equal to 400 so valid represent the data of the new newly created
No.
So 400 is equal to valid and we are inserting A..
That contains data equal to 400, which creates tracked node new node, and we reserve the memory by
using outlook.
We allocate the memory by using this method and we create new node data is equal to that.
We assign the data of the new node.
Data is equal to value the following part of me, which is that OK.
Now we check if had equal equal to now, then you know, next.
Equal to new note and had equal to new note, OK?
If the head is referring to, then not.
Now, if we don't have this, there was the following or the previous case of not having any any notes,
we are inserting it at the first.
If there is notes here and we are going to insert it at the first, then create a temporary note called
damp.
And this point, to refer it to the high head and the start using the while loop temp next does not
equal to head temp equals temp, don't next.
As I told you in the previous video that the end.
And the trick behind using the circular link is that you should pay attention for it.
That reaching the end of the linked list or the circular linkage list is not by searching and for the
next equal to null note because the circular linked list where if the last node inside it were fair
and the reference as to the first note.
So this is the trick.
Temp Dot next does not equal to had.
So the next pointer and the next note is not referring us to the head.
So we're still here.
We reach the end of the circular linked list while having that -- dot next equal to the head.
So pay attention for this guy.
It's very important temp next equal to a new note and the new note next equal to had and then have equal
to, you know, it's very simple, but you should pay attention about where we should stop.
What is the condition of this?
What is the stopping condition of the look, which is the temp next equal to head?
And that's not equal to had this is the stopping condition of the way.
And you should pay attention for that for two things that the reference of the last one should be should
be changed to the newly created one at the beginning and the newly created note should the reference
to the next.
What does the next note, which was the head of that linked list before insertion?
OK.
Two things concerning that reference.
And one thing that you should pay attention that is the breaking of the loop and the condition that
we should stop at.
It is reaching the term equal to had because we have started from the head.
And if I reach the head again in a circular link, at least, then we have reached the end of the circular
link at least.
OK.